Register of the Milton Edward Miles papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Milton Edward Miles papers
1923-1958
68028
Hoover Institution Archives
9 manuscript boxes, 4 envelopes (4.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, notes, orders, and photographs relating to the Sino-Japanese Conflict, U.S.- Chinese relations during World War II, post-war military defense in Latin America, Canadian-U.S. joint defense policies, and the Indochina and Korean Wars. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Miles, Milton E., 1900-1961
Access
Collection open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1968.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1900 April 6 Born, Jerome, Arizona, son of Lewis E. Robbins and Mae Belle Cook, stepson of George A. Miles
1917 Apprentice seaman, U.S. Navy
1918-1922 Midshipman, U.S. Naval Academy
1922-1927 Commissioned as Ensign and promoted to Lieutenant (Junior Grade), U.S. Asiatic Fleets
1927-1929 Post Graduate School, U.S. Naval Academy
1928 Promoted to Lieutenant
1929 M.S., Columbia University
1929-1932 Electrical officer, U.S.S. Saratoga
1932-1934 Member, Bureau of Engineering, Navy Department
1934-1939 Destroyer duty, U.S. Pacific and Asiatic Fleets
1937 Promoted to Lieutenant Commander
1939-1942 Member, Interior Control Board, Navy Department
1942 Promoted to Commander and Captain
1942-1943 U.S. Naval Observer, Chung King, China and Chief of OSS (Office of Strategic Services) for the Far East
1943-1945 Deputy Director, Sino-American Cooperative Organization (SACO)
1944-1945 Commander, U.S. Naval Group, China
1945 Appointed Rear Admiral, for temporary service
1946 Commanding Officer, U.S.S. Columbus
1947 Planning Officer, Staff of Commander Service Force, Atlantic Fleet
1948 Promoted to Rear Admiral
1948 Commander, Cruiser Division One
1949 Commander, Cruiser Division Six
1949 Commander, Cruiser Division Four
1950-1954 Director, Pan American Affairs and U.S. Naval Missions in the Office of the Chief of Naval Operations and Senior Naval Delegate to Inter-American Defense Board
1954 Commandant, Fifteenth Naval District, Panama Canal Zone
1955 On-site Commander, Operation Friendship, flood relief program, Tampico, Mexico
1956 Commandant, Third Naval District, New York, and Commander, U.S. Naval Base, New York
1958 Promoted and retired as Vice Admiral
1961 March 25 Died
1967 Author (posthumously) A Different Kind of War: The Little-Known Story of the Combined Guerilla Forces Created in China by the U.S. Navy and the Chinese during World War II
Inter-American Defense Board.; Permanent Joint Board on Defense (Canada-United States); Sino-American Cooperative Organization.; United States. Navy--Officers.; Canada--Military relations--United States.; Canada.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China.; Indochinese War, 1946-1954.; Korean War, 1950-1953.; Latin America--Military relations--United States.; Latin America.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Military relations--Canada.; United States--Military relations--Latin America.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1938-1958 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Alley, Rewi, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Alger, Ambassador Frederick M., Jr., 1954
  - Arias, Harmodio, 1956
  - Baly, Commandant M., France, 1949
  - Barringer, William, 1946
  - Baruch, Bernard M., Jr., 1958
  - Beebe, M. U., 1949
  - Beyerly, Commander Irving F., 1946-1951
  - Bibby, Lowe H., 1950
  - Blandy, Admiral W. H. P., 1948
  - Bledsoe, Rear Admiral A. M., 1950, 1957
  - Blick, R. E., 1948
  - Bookhamer, Commander R. H., 1957
  - Bowman, Commander George, 1945
  - Bowen, Vice Admiral Harold G., 1950
  - Brannan, Secretary of Agriculture Charles F., 1951
  - Brennecke, Margaret, 1949
  - Brown, Vice Admiral Charles ("Cat"), 1957
  - Brown, Dayton R. E., 1942
  - Bruggemann, Major Lester G. (Gus), 1945
  - Brunet, Meade, 1947, 1949, 1954
  - Bullitt, Ambassador William C., 1949
  - Burkhart, H. W., Jr., 1949
  - Burke, Admiral Arleigh A., 1948, 1956-1957
  - Byes, Donald F., 1949
  - Calvert, Commander James, 1957
  - Campbell, Air Vice Marshall Hugh, Canada, 1950
  - Campbell, General Thomas D., 1949
  - Cannon, J. B., 1951
  - Capieto, Rudolph, 1946
  - Champe, Joseph E., 1950
  - Chan, Anna, 1947
  - Chang, Chun, 1957
  - Chang, Wan-ying, 1945 (?)
  - Chen, Chih-Ping, 1948, 1951
  - Chen, Yao-hung, 1946
  - Cheng, General Kai-Ming, Republic of China, 1946-1948, 1954
  - Chiang, General Ching-Kuo, Republic of China, 1956
  - Chiang, Generalissimo Kai-shek, Republic of China, 1945-1946, 1948, 1954, 1957
  - Chiang, (Madame) Kai-shek, 1942, 1950
  - Chennault, Major General Claire L., 1946-1947, 1958
  - Chu, Y. L., 1947
  - Clark, Admiral D. H., 1957
  - Cochran, Commander D. E., 1946
  - Cochran, S. W., 1941
  - Coffin, Elizabeth, 1951
  - Colbert, Dr. John W., 1955-1956
  - Coleman, Dr. Ernest H., 1946
  - Cramer, Leigh R., 1956
  - Daly, Paul A., 1952
  - Dealy, Roland, 1950
  - Diaz, Emilio, 1956-1957
  - Dietrich, Neil, 1949
  - Dobbins, C. G., 1945-1946
  - Dornin, Captain Marshall E., 1956
  - Drake, Waldo, 1948
  - Duval, Captain Miles P., 1950
  - Earnshaw, Fenton W., 194?-1946
  - Earnshaw, Harry A., 1946
  - Eastman, R. J., 1947-1948
  - Eccles, Henry E., 1957
  - Eckberg, Captain H. F., 1947, 1950
  - Efron, George A., 1949, 1951-1952
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1949
  - Eller, Rear Admiral Ernest M. (Judge), 1942, 1949, 1957
  - Emblanc, Colonel, Fighting French Military Mission, 1943
  - Eraso, Jaime Annexy, 1957
  - First Aid for Hungary, Inc., 1956
  - Fisher, A. L., 1940
  - Fitzpatrick, Commander J. P., 1956
  - Forester, C. S., 1956
  - Forrestal, Secretary of Defense James, 1948-1949
  - Galantin, Commander I. J. (Pete), 1945, 1952
  - Galvez, Juan Manuel, 1954
  - Gardner, Ambassador Arthur, 1954
  - Garnett, Captain P. W., 1957
  - Gilfillan, Ruth, 1945
  - Giraud, General Henri, France, 1946
  - Goldberg, Captain Joshua L., 1957
  - Goodwin, Dr. Robert H., 1946, 1949
  - Grable, Colonel Jack, 1949
  - Green, Thomas, 1955
  - Grover, Preston L., 1949
  - Guardia, Ernesto de la, President of Panama, 1956
  - Haatvedt, Rollo, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Halsey, Admiral William F., 1957
  - Hammond, Mr. and Mrs. S. A., Jr., 1956
  - Hardy, Congressman Porter, Jr., 1956
  - Harriman, Governor Averell, 1956
  - Haselton, N. S., 1957
  - Heagy, Lieutenant Commander Daniel Webster, 1947
  - Healey, Roy, 1946
  - Herren, Lieutenant General Thomas W., 1957
  - Heimburg, Rear Admiral E. H. von, 1950-1952
  - Hoffman, Dr. Rolla E., 1942
  - Hofmann, Dean, 1957
  - Holloway, Rear Admiral J. L., 1949
  - Holmes, Captain W. J., 1946
  - Hon, George S. Y., 1946
  - Horton, John, 1947
  - Hsiao, Colonel Sin-ju, Republic of China, 1945, 1948-1950, 1955
  - Huang, Bessie, 1951
  - Huang, Siu-feng, 1951
  - Hurley, General Patrick, Jr., 1948
  - Hurt, Willie F., 1941
  - Hwang, Deputy Commissioner You, Republic of China, 1947
  - Hwang, (Mrs.) Z., 1947
  - Ironmonger, Commander Richard, 1958
  - Jones, Richard E., 1956
  - Kendig, Richard and Dorothy, 1955
  - Kimball, Lieutenant Commander K. W., 1957
  - Kimmel, Admiral Husband E., 1941, 1950, 1958
  - Kotrla, Ray, 1952
  - Kunjara, Colonel Karb and Tieb, Thailand, 1947
  - Kunjara, Toy, 1949
  - Kwei, Paul (Chi-ting), 1946-1947
  - Land, Edwin H., 1947
  - Lane, Most Reverand Raymond A., 1951
  - Langen, Commander T. E. F., 1945
  - Larco, Rafael Herrera, 1951, 1954
  - Larson, Robert P., 1946
  - Lawlar (?), Bill, 1947
  - LeBarre, Weston, 1950
  - Lee, General Chung-shih, 1945-1947
  - Lee, Tai-Yih, 1945
  - Lee, Rear Admiral Young Woon, Republic of Korea, 1957
  - Liang, Admiral Hsu-Chao, Commander-in-Chief, Chinese Navy, 1957
  - Lin, Captain P. C. (Charles), 1951
  - Liu, Lieutenant Colonel Cheng Fong (Eddie), Republic of China, 1946, 1950, 1952
  - Liu, Frederick F., 1947, 1951, 1956
  - Longton, Captain E. W., 1957
  - Looney, Jack and Joyce, 1955
  - Lynch, R. E., 1949
  - Ma, General Chi-Chow, Republic of China, 1947
  - Ma, Vice Admiral Chi Chuang, Republic of China, 1954
  - McCaffrey, Lieutenant Commander Stanley E., 1945
  - McGaha, F. Leroy, 1946, 1948
  - McNaughton, General A. G. L., 1955
  - Madden, Lieutenant Commander Vic G., 1947
  - Manson, Lieutenant Commander Frank A., 1947
  - Mao, (Mrs.) Hsiang-Hsing, 1957
  - Mao, General Jen-Feng, Republic of China, 1946-1947, 1950
  - Mao, General Shen, Republic of China, 1947
  - Mar, Timothy T., 1957
  - Metzell, Captain Jeffrey C., 1938, 1949
  - Meyertholen, Lieutenant Commander Joe, 1946, 1949
  - Meynier, Commander Robert and Madame Kathiou Do Huu Thinh, France, 1943, 1945, 1947-1949
  - Miles, Mrs. Milton E. ("Billy"), (holographs), 1946-1947, 1950, 1955
  - Milliren, Howard C., and Pearl, 1946, 1948-1949, 1951
  - Moll, Mr. and Mrs. Peter, 1945-1946, 1948-1949
  - Morison, Samuel Elliot, 1957
  - Morris, S. I. (Si), 1946
  - Mountbatten, Rear Admiral the Earl, Great Britain, 1948
  - National War College, 1951
  - Naval War College, 1949-1950, 1958
  - Nimitz, Fleet Admiral Chester W., 1948
  - Norton, Edward, 1949-1950
  - Oard, Harry C., 1956 (Box 3)
  - Opie, Captain John N., 1947
  - Owen, Lieutenant Commander Emmett, 1957
  - Pan, General Chi-wu, 1947, 1950, 1952-1953
  - Pan, John, 1949
  - Parkin, Charles M., 1948, 1950
  - Pechkoff, General Vinovi, 1946
  - Peterson, Bruce A., 1952
  - Plake, F. Marvin, 1946
  - Podmaniczky, Sandor, 1946
  - Pottle, Mrs. V. L. (Edna), 1945
  - Ragan, Rear Admiral Thomas C., 1957
  - Robinson, Commander Reuel V., 1946
  - Rojas, Contraalmirante Isaac F., 1958
  - Rousset, Major J. F., 1947-1948
  - Ruiz Cortines, Adolio, President of Mexico, 1958
  - Saldias, Admiral Rouge A., Peru, 1957
  - Salisbury, Stanton W., 1949-1950
  - San Diego Zoological Gardens, 1946
  - Savage, S. S., 1948
  - Scott, Hoyt S., 1945
  - Shen, Yin, 1945
  - Slonim, Gilven M., 1957
  - Smith, Rear Admiral Allan E., 1948
  - Smith, Captain C. D., 1950
  - Smith, Francis H., 1945
  - Smith, Ward J. ("Smitty"; Ehr Shih Li), 1945-1949, 1956, 1958
  - Smoot, Captain Roland N., 1947
  - Spellman, Cardinal Francis, 1950
  - Stimson, Robert, 1947
  - Stratton, Commander Roy O., 1945, 1949-1950
  - Su, Hsin-min, 1945
  - Symand, Louis, undated
  - Tai, General Li, Republic of China, 1942, 1945-1946
  - Tai, Madame Lao Tai, 1946
  - Talbot, Philips, 1957
  - Tao, General Yi-shan, Republic of China, 1947-1948
  - Tayloe, Dr. G. B., 1948
  - Taylor, W. L., 1941
  - Tetrault, Ernie, 1956
  - Thomas, Secretary of the Navy Charles S., 1956-1957
  - Thompson, H. Keith, 1956
  - Thurrell, Robert F., 1955
  - Tong, Ambassador Hollington K., 1957
  - Tong, General Tsung, Republic of China, 1947
  - Trefny, Commander W. P., Jr., 1953
  - Tsen, Captain T. C., 1957
  - United States Naval Institute, 1946, 1953
  - United States Naval ROTC Unit, Cornell University, 1957
  - Utley, Freda, 1951
  - Wales, George H., 1957
  - Wells, Commander Tom H., 1956
  - Whitten Major General Lyman P., 1951
  - Wight, Dave, 1951
  - Williams, H. S. (Hal), 1951
  - Wright, Rear Admiral C. H., 1945
  - Wu, Amy H., 1950
  - Wu, General Te-Chen, Republic of China, 1939, 1947
  - Yee, Frank, 1951
  - Young, Mrs. E. W. ("La Mary"), ca. 1950
  - Yuan, Ching-yuen, 1952
  - Unidentified letters
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1949-1957 (Box 3)
  Printed and typescript copies of speeches, arranged alphabetically by title, and handwritten notes.
  - "Important Police Activities in Wartime China," address before the Fifty-Seventh Annual Conference of the New York State Association of Chiefs of Police, 1957 July 24 (Box 3)
  - "Navy Supply and Logistics Problems in China during W.W. II," remarks made before the U.S. Naval Supply Depot Supervisor's luncheon, 1957
  - Secret memorandum concerning U.S. intelligence service organization in China, sent to the Chief of the Information Branch, Central Planning Staff, Central Intelligence Group, 1946 May 17
  - Notes
- SUBJECT FILE, 1923-1958 (Boxes 4-9)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, position papers, charts, histories, maps, lists, notes, observations, orders, speeches, printed materials, clippings, circulars, rosters, messages, and photographs, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Alaska (Box 4)
    - Alaska Railroad
    - U.S. Naval Petroleum Reserve No. 4, 1952
  - Chennault, Major General Claire L., 1945-1948
  - China
    - General
      Includes declassified records returned to file after November 2015 release by Hoover.
      - Maps
      - News clippings
    - Chao Hon Middle School
    - China-Burma Highway, report of trip made by Milton E. Miles, 1939
    - Chinese Railway, engineers and administrative officials, 1945
    - Communism
    - Currency, comparative chart of exchange and the price index of the Associated Church Treasurers in the period, 1937-1945
    - Flood relief, delivery of supplies to the U.S. Marine detachment, Tientsin, China, 1939 August
    - Junks and sampans, descriptive notes by Lieutenant Howard Bucknell, 1953
    - Kamikaze Ships, report concerning the disconnection of the motors of such ships in the Chushan Archipelago area, 1945
    - Missionaries, article about "How the 'Reds' Drove American Missionaries from Wuchow" by Charles Daily in The China Weekly Review, 1926 July 17
    - Sino-American Cooperative Organization (SACO) (Box 5)
      - Ionospheric project, settlement of payment for services
      - SACO-The Rice Paddy Navy by Roy Olin Stratton, Pleasantville, New York: C. S. Palmer Publishing Co., unbound printed copy, 1950
      - Training of Chinese guerillas
    - Sino-Japanese Conflict
      - Japanese Army circular, 1939
      - Snow, Edgar, "The What-the-Hell Pennant," Saturday Evening Post, 1945 November 10
      - "Some Phases of the Sino-Japanese Conflict (July to December, 1937)," by Captain W. A. Angwin, 1938 December
      - U.S. Naval Intelligence reports, 1937, 1939
    - U.S. Naval Group, China
      - Correspondence, memoranda, messages
      - "An Official History of the United States Naval Group, China,", 1946
      - "Operational Report on U.S. Naval Group, China," an essay submitted to the Department of English History and Government, United States Naval Academy, by Midshipman W. B. Miles, 1952 March
      - Postal Service, history, 1945 September 15
      - Postwar relations with Chinese government, 1947
      - Receipts and expenditures, 1942-1944
    - U.S. Military attache personnel, 1951
  - China Emergency Committee
  - Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy
  - Communism
  - French Military Mission in the Far East
  - Greece, personalities in Athens, 1949
  - Guerilla warfare
  - H.M.S. Rodney, inspection visit, 1940
  - Indo-China War, 1947-1954
  - Indonesia
  - International Naval Review, Hampton Roads, Virginia, 1957 June
  - Korean War
  - Latin America
    - General (Box 6)
    - Argentina
      - General
      - "La Campaña Antartica (The Antarctic Company), 1951-1952," article by Emilio L. Diaz
      - Peron, Juan, inauguration, 1952
      - Political and military affairs
      - Tierra del Fuego
      - U.S. relations with the Argentine Navy
    - Bolivia
      - General
      - Bolivian attitude on regional disarmament, 1955
      - Economic aid
    - Brazil
      - General
      - Anti-American propaganda
      - Brazilian National Security Council
      - Miles, Admiral Milton E., official visit, 1952
      - Political and military affairs
      - U.S. Naval Mission
      - U.S. relations with the Brazilian Navy
    - Chile
      - Miles, Admiral Milton E., official visit, 1951
      - Political and economic affairs, U.S. relations with the Chilean Navy
    - Colombia
      - General
      - Miles, Admiral Milton E., official visits, 1951, 1955
      - Piedrahita, Admiral Ruben
      - Political and military affairs
      - Sinking of the schooner Resolute
      - U.S. Naval Mission
      - U.S. relations with the Colombian Navy
    - Costa Rica (Box 7)
      - Pan-American Highway
      - Political and military affairs
      - U.S. relations with Costa Rica
    - Cuba
      - Political affairs
      - U.S. relations with Cuba
    - Dominican Republic
      - General
      - Cabot, John Moors, political observation tour, 1953
      - U.S. relations with the Dominican Navy
    - Ecuador
      - General
      - Estero-Salvado/Puerto Nuevo project
      - Plaza Lasso, President Galo
      - Political affairs and border disputes
      - United States Government Operations, summary report, 1955
      - U.S. Naval Mission
    - El Salvador
      - Training of El Salvador Coast Guard officers aboard U.S. naval vessels and political affairs
    - Guatemala
      - Guatemalan military personnel
      - Political affairs
    - Haiti
      - U.S. relations with the Haitian Navy
    - Honduras
      - Political affairs
    - Inter-American Defense Board
    - Mexico
      - General
      - Flood relief in Tampico (Operaciòn de Amistad/Operation Friendship), 1955
      - Military decorations
      - Military parades
      - Return to Mexico of flags caputured in the War of 1846-1848
      - Ruiz Cortines, President Adolfo, inauguration, 1952
      - Salinas Carranza, General Alberto, Director of Civil Aviation
      - U.S. relations with the Mexican Navy
    - Nicaragua
      - Somoza, President Anastasio
    - Panama (Box 8)
      - General
      - Assassination of President Jose Antonio Remon, 1955
      - Celebration of the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Independence of the Republic of Panama, 1953
      - Overland trail from David to Chiriquicito
      - Panama Canal
      - Panama Railroad
      - Political, economic, and diplomatic affairs
        - 1954 January - 1955 August
        - 1955 September - 1956 March
      - U.S. relations with Panama
    - Paraguay
      - Miles, Admiral Milton E., official visit (includes photographs), 1955
    - Peru
      - General
      - Border controversy between Peru and Ecuador
      - Crops and livestock, reply by United States Operations Mission to an inquiry by Arnold J. Toynbee
      - Maritime technical assistance
      - Miles, Admiral Milton E., trip on the Marañón and Ucayali Rivers, 1954
      - Peruvian naval interests
      - Transporation and sanitary conditions along the Amazon River
      - U.S. Naval Mission
      - U.S. relations with Peru
    - Uruguay
      - General
      - Martinez Trueba, President Andrés, inauguration, 1951 March
    - Venezuela
      - Betancourt, Romulo
      - Larrazabal Ugueto, Wolgan
      - Military personnel
  - Miles, Admiral Milton E. (Box 9)
    - General
    - Biographies and vitae
    - Citations, commendations, letters of appreciation
    - Papers of Admiral Miles relating to New York Naval District, notes on
    - Return trip from China, 1945
  - Neutralism in Asia
  - "Operation-Remember" (Honoring Wartime Leaders and Enlisted Heroes of the U.S. Navy and Marine Corps), 1957 May
  - Pearl Harbor, Admiral Husband E. Kimmel's reply to the remarks of Congressman Clarence Cannon concerning the Japanese attack in December, 1941, 1958
  - Permanent Joint Board on Defense (Canada-United States)
    - General
    - Canadian National Defense College and Army Staff College
    - Fort Churchill, Manitoba
    - Frobisher Bay, Royal Canadian Air Force unit
    - U.S. Naval Ordinance Test Station, China Lake
  - Tai, General Li, death and funeral services, 1946-1947
  - Turkey
    - American fleet visit, 1949
    - Joint Military Mission for Aid to Turkey, officer personnel, 1951
  - U.S. Army, Arctic orientation tours, 1951-1952
  - U.S., Department of State, relations with Latin America, address by John M. Cabot, Assistant Secretary of State for Inter-American affairs, 1953 October 9 and 14
  - U.S. Navy
    - Administration, principles and problems
    - Inspection of defense project facilities (Bell Telephone Laboratory, RCA Victor Company, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Sperry Gyroscope Company, Bendix Company, Electro Dynamic Companies), by M. E. Miles, 1940-1941
    - Inspection of U.S. Naval Missions in Ecuador, Colombia, Venezuela, and Haiti, memorandum by E. J. Foster
    - Naval interests in Latin America
    - Personnel, Asiatic Fleet and Station, 1939-1941
    - U.S.S. Atlantic, sinking of vessel, 1942
    - U.S.S. John D. Edwards, loss of ration records, 1942
    - U.S.S. Juneau, sinking of the vessel, 1942
    - U.S.S. Panay, inquiry into the sinking of the vessel, 1937
    - U.S.S. Preble, visit to Kobe, Japan, 1923
    - U.S.S. Saratoga, special report on detachment by Lieutenant Jeffrey C. Metzel, 1930
  - U.S. Senate
    - Investigation of Communism by the Subcommittee on Internal Security of the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, 1955
  - Yu, General Ta-Wei, biographical data, 1951
  - Zikawei Observatory, 1946
  - Miscellaneous
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE (Photo file)
  General note
  Four envelopes. See photo file card index.
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1954
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfield records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2010 release of records, 1954 (Reading room workstation)
    Available as PDF files. Arranged chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2015 November release of records, 1950s
    See individual folders in SUBJECT FILE series.
  - 2017 release of records, 1952-1955